Guide to the Dave Martin Photographs of Male Nudes
Department of Special Collections
Dave Martin Photographs of male nudes,
1951-1974
Mss Photo 217
Martin, Dave
12.5 linear ft. 21 manuscript boxes, 3 flat boxes (ca. 2600 photographs)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Martin's photos are of young men, indoors and out, including body builders, college athletes, military and law enforcement men. He refers to his photography genre in a recently published book as male physique photography, tracing the history of the genre back to the 1920s, 30s and 40s.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Dave Martin, 2003.
Biography / Administrative History
Dave Martin became San Francisco's first photographer to specialize in male nude physique studies when he opened his Sacramento Street studio in San Francisco in 1952.
Martin was born and raised in Pennsylvania. In the 1940s he met Lon Hanagan of New York and was inspired by his photographic skills. At that point in time, Hanagan was acknowledged to be the best photographer of the male form in the United States.
Determined to create his own portfolio of physique photographs of young men, Martin became a self-taught photographer of reknown. He controlled all aspects of his photograpy, from posing his models, processing film and doing his own darkroom printing.
His preferred media was black &white film; he started with a 4x5 Super D Graflex, a camera made famous in the 1920s, then later switched to a 4x5 Crown Graphic with electronic flash. Most sessions were 60 shots made on Super Pan Press film, some of which utilized filters for dramatic effect. He controlled his photographic process every step of the way. Dave quickly became known for his darkroom proficiency and the very high quality prints he produced.
Dave Martin photographed all-American young men indoors and out, and was the first to use San Francisco's landmark Golden Gate Bridge, in the 50s as a backdrop for his nudes. While some of Martin's models were young bodybuilders, many were college athletes, men in military service and others came from law enforcement.
Of interest to Stanford researchers is the fact that many of his models were student athletes from Stanford University.
Martin's physique photographs were published in men's muscle magazines of the period. They appeared in Strength &Health, Tomorrow's Man, Vim, Body Beautiful, and others.
His career was at its peak between 1951 and 1974. He currently resides in San Francisco.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection contains ca. 2,600 original photographs by Martin of young men in both indoor studio settings and outdoor locations, including body builders, college athletes, military and law enforcement men. He refers to his photography genre in a recently published book as male physique photography, tracing the history of the genre back to the 1920s, 30s and 40s.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into 8 series, the first of which are original Dave Martin photographs. Series 1: Caucasian Athletes is comprised of images of caucasian athletes and models. Series 2: Black athletes is comprised of images of African American athletes and models. Series 3: Mixed Athletes is comprised of images of European- and African-American athletes and models. Series 4: Back poses are also a mixture of images of European- and African-American athletes and models. Within each of the boxes containing original photography of nude males by Dave Martin, the photographs are arranged alphabetically by model, following the original arrangement scheme employed by Dave Martin.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Martin, Dave, photographer.; Male nude in art.; Photography, Erotic--San Francisco (Calif.); Photography of men.; Photography of the nude.
Separated Material
Several books were removed from the collection and cataloged as part of the Rare Books Division. They can be located by using Stanford's Online Catalog, Socrates, and searching using the keyword search "Dave Martin Photographs of Male Nudes".
Collection Contents
- Caucasian (White) athletes, 1951-1974, Series 1
  - Jerry Baxter, 1953, 6 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bill Brannan, 1955, 6 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Don Coates, 1953, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dave Ellis - outdoors, 1953, 4 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Al Emerson, 1954, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Rob Gibson, 1970, 4 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ralph Gomes, 1965, 13 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Fred Jensen, 1955, 2 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Jerry La Rosa, 1966, 2 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Doug Madison, 1953, 6 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Terry Marcellus, 1974, 12 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Chuck Miller - outdoors, 1953, 9 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Chris Mitchell, 1954, 3 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Larry O'Brien, 1953, 5 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Mike Sill, 1956, 4 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Fred Somers, 1968, 1 photograph: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Lee Stevenson, 1965, 3 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bob Thomas, 1968, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Zaro [Rossi], 1953, 9 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Ross Allen, 1955, 4 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Ralph Blumenthal, 1954, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Gary Brandon, Stanford University athlete, 1965, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Ben Carter, Stanford University athlete, 1965, 14 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Jim Elliot, U.C. Berkeley, 1968, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Tony Farrell - beach scenes, 1952, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Jim Hamilton, 1965, 5 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Keith Hanson, Stanford athlete, 1953, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Max Milan, Stanford athlete, 1966, 3 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Mark Peterson, 1966, 11 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Paul Revak, Stanford athlete, 1955, 5 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - John Silva, 1964, 10 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Paul Simone, 1953, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Rick Sylvester, 1965, 12 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Dale Wasson, 1951, 6 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Dexter Young, 1966, 6 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Don Barry, 1968, 4 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Jack Caruso, 1952, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Ray Christopher, 1953, 13 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - John Connor, U.C. Berkeley athlete, 1954, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Jason Donovan, 1965, 4 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - John Gledhill, 1968, 16 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Jay Holt, 1965, 11 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Merrill Jacobs, 1952, 11 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - John Julian, 1953, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Ford Reynolds, 1972, 10 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Vern Richards, 1953, 11 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Don Robinson, 1953, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Marvin Spence, 1955, 4 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bob Travers, 1969, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Chuck Tyson, 1969, 3 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Larry Briggs, U.C. Berkeley athlete, 1966, 6 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Jerry Cooper, Stanford University athlete, 1968, 13 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Paul Dixon, 1953, 12 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Ken Dockter, 1951, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Dennis Flynn, n.d., 15 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Joe Henderson, 1966, 9 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Jeff Leonard, 1973, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Jay Miller, Stanford University athlete, 1974, 13 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Jeff Richardson, Stanford University athlete, 1973, 9 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Richard Rose, U.C. Berkeley athlete, 1971, 3 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Dick Scott, 1952, 9 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Gene Stanley, 1953, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Joe Tingey - portrait, 1952, 3 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Mike Vernon, 1955, 4 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Eric Winslow, 1953, 4 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Frank Alvarez - portrait, 1970, 2 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Scott Carpenter, 1966, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Jerry Catron - portrait, 1956, 1 photograph: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - John Chapman, 1971, 6 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Dick Curtis, n.d., Note: none found (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Sam Mayo, 1953, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Dick Norman, 1952, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Noel Slocum, 1966, 5 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Dave St. Denis, 1969, 12 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Jody Sutherland, U.C. Berkeley athlete, 1968, 18 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Norm Tousley - outdoors, 1953, 11 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Bob Whaley - portrait, 1955, 1 photograph: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Bill Woodruff, 1969, 15 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Zaro [Rossi] - studio, 1953, 16 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Ross Allen - outdoors, 1955, 6 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Greg Bradford, 1955, 12 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Larry Crawford, 1965, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Walt Davis, 1956, 4 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Ray Harper, 1955, 3 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bob Kilpatrick, 1952, 3 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Andy Kozak, 1954, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Don Larson, 1953, 6 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Jon Mason, U.C. Berkeley athlete, 1965, 9 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Ron McNeal - portraits, 1955, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Bob Miller, 1953, 9 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Bob Morris, 1952, 5 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Ray Routledge, 1951, 9 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Ed Siemens, 1953, 12 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Norm Tousley - studio, 1953, 16 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Jarvis Watson, Stanford University athlete, 1955, 3 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Dick Woodward, 1956, 5 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Richard Wright, 1966, 4 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Sandy Alcorn, 1955, 12 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Brian Benson, n.d., 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Bob Bethea, 1955, 1 photograph: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Keith Richardson, 1955, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Bud Counts, 1955, 14 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Tom Fine, 1953, 6 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Cliff Harris, Stanford University athlete, 1968, 9 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Tim Hogan, 1966, 9 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Bob Johnson, 1953, 3 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Roy Lang, 1953, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Pete Lee, 1951, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Rick Russell, 1951, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Randy Saunders, 1969, 18 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Marv Toleson, 1953, 1 photograph: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Jim Warren, U.C. Berkeley, 1953, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Ron Weaver - portraits, 1970, 1 photograph: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Tom West, 1965, 16 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Jim Carson, 1968, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Steve Clayton, 1965, 9 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - John Jurgenson - portraits, Stanford University athletes, 1964, 1 photograph: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Lance Kendrick, 1965, 12 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Fred Martinez, 1966, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Joe Mason, 1952, 6 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Mike McMillan, 1953, 9 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Walt Montgomery, 1964, 18 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Brad Payne, 1953, 5 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Reed & Johnson - duals, 1953, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Perry Stevenson, 1965, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Carl Wadlow, 1955, 6 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Charlie Wall, 1968, 10 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Don Brown, 1953, 6 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Mason Brown, 1953, 3 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Robbie Carson - portrait, 1954, 2 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Jerry Cooper - portrait, Stanford University athlete, 1968, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Craig Dickson, Stanford University athlete, 1969, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Richard Kelly, 1952, 9 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Jimmy La Spina, 1966, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Cliff Lopez, 1973, 23 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - John Manning, 1966, 10 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Charlie Masch, Stanford University athlete, 1973, 11 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Chuck Miller - studio, 1953, 10 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Paul Ramirez, 1974, 9 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Tom Roan, 1972, 12 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Bruce Sein - portrait, 1953, 5 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Glenn R. Smith, 1974, 15 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Glen Wolf, 1956, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Ken Booth, 1968, 4 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Bob Bowen, 1953, 5 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Jack Brent, 1953, 4 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Doyle Brewer, 1955, 6 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Rusty Carlson, 1968, 5 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Rick Dayton, Stanford University athlete, 1969, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Don Detata, n.d., Note: none found (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Gary Dexter, 1953, 10 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Bill Elliot, 1956, 2 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Dave Ellis - studio, 1953, 4 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Kevin Hall, 1971, 10 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Dick Jacobs, 1953, 2 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Mike Jones, Stanford University athlete, 1954, 10 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Peter Lederer, 1953, 4 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Tyler Livingston, 1968, 2 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Vic Nelson, 1953, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Dave Sanchez, 1968, 5 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Dale Smith - studio, 1956, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Norm Spangler, n.d., 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Gary Sullivan, 1966, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Scott Sullivan, 1956, 5 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Roy Allen, 1953, 1 photograph: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Richard Amandoli, 1951, 4 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Grant Bafford, 1968, 5 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Craig Bondy, Stanford University athlete, 1969, 14 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Manny Costa, 1952, 3 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Dick Curtis, 1953, 6 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Jack Edwards, 1952, 5 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Jack Keen, 1953, 2 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Dick Ludolph, Stanford University athlete, 1951, 2 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Zack Ramsey, 1954, 1 photograph: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Gary Smith, 1954, 5 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Bob Thompson, 1954, 9 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Two U.S. Navy men, 1954, 1 photograph: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Jack Wells, Stanford University athlete, 1974, 11 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Wesley, 1965, 1 photograph: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Ray Wilson, 1972, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Charles York, 1951, 1 photograph: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Various portraits & sport shots: Bill Brannan, 1955, 5 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Various portraits & sport shots: miscellaneous, 1970, 3 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Bob Mathias, Stanford University athlete: portraits, 1952, 4 photographs: b&w; 36 x 28 cm. (Othertype 23)
  - Dale Wasson: portrait, 1951, 1 photograph: b&w; 51 x 41 cm. (Othertype 24)
- Black athletes1951-1974, Series 2
  - King Collins, 1966, 10 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Justin Delancy, 1964, 17 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Bob Fischer, 1970, 15 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - John Fortson, 1956, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Joe Green, 1964, 12 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Kenny Mitchell, 1965, 22 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Virgil Owens, 1965, 18 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Bruce Reed, 1968, 19 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Maurice Spencer, 1969, 14 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Joe Carroll, 1965, 12 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Calvin Dunbar, 1970, 10 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Bill Edwards [1 of 2], 1965, 20 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Bill Edwards [2 of 2], 1965, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Al Savoy, 1969, 9 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Jerry Tucker [1 of 3], 1968, 20 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Jerry Tucker [2 of 3], 1968, 20 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Jerry Tucker [3 of 3], 1968, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Robert Baker [1 of 2], 1970, 20 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Robert Baker [2 of 2], 1970, 20 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Robert Swift, 1966, 1 photograph: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Earl Corley, 1965, 23 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Jim Jenkins, 1968, 12 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Walt Jourdan, 1952, 9 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Kevin Matson [1 of 3], 1968, 20 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Kevin Matson [2 of 3], 1968, 20 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Kevin Matson [3 of 3], 1968, 6 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Jerome Woods, 1965, 16 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Fred Armstrong [1 of 2], 1970, 20 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Fred Armstrong [2 of 2], 1970, 6 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Robert Lee Carter, 1970, 12 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Jim Ferguson, Stanford University athlete [1 of 2], 1973, 20 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Jim Ferguson, Stanford University athlete [2 of 2], 1973, 4 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Alfred Pendleton, 1968, 13 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Phil St. James, U.C. Berkeley athlete, 1968, 23 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - John Williams, U.C. Berkeley athlete, 1965, 4 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Chris Dupont, 1956, 9 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Gary Lewis, 1965, 19 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Andre Little, 1970, 22 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Wayne Stribling, 1966, 22 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Josh Webster [1 of 2], 1971, 20 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Josh Webster [2 of 2], 1971, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Roy Campbell, 1968, 22 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Leroy Davis [1 of 2], 1967, 20 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Leroy Davis [2 of 2], 1967, 8 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Steve Radd [1 of 2], 1967, 20 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Steve Radd [2 of 2], 1967, 7 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Various portraits & sport shots: John Fortson, 1955, 1 photograph: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Various portraits & sport shots: Ollie Matson, 1952, 4 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. + 1 clipping (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Various portraits & sport shots: Formus White, 1968, 2 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Various portraits & sport shots: Ron Weaver, 1970, 3 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Various portraits & sport shots: miscellaneous, 1968 - 1970, 5 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Don McKinney, baseball & football player [1 of 4], 1971, 20 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Don McKinney, baseball & football player [2 of 4], 1971, 20 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Don McKinney, baseball & football player [3 of 4], 1971, 20 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Don McKinney, baseball & football player [4 of 4], 1971, 10 photographs: b&w; 26 x 21 cm. (Box 18, Folder 4)